The Night of the Tragedy
（ダンゾウ）任務の増加に伴い
暗部の班を増やすことにした。
Due to an increasing amount of assignments,
I've decided to add
an additional team to the ANBU.
その隊長を　イタチ　お前に任せる。
（イタチ）はっ。
Itachi, I'm appointing you captain.
Yes, sir.
I'm not opposed,
but you are very young.
反対はせぬが
しかし　若いのう。
いくつだ？
１３です。
How old are you?
I'm thirteen.
もっと若くして上忍になった忍は
いくらでもいる。
There are a number of shinobi who
were younger and have become jonin.
暗部入りして　２年で隊長か。
Just two years in the ANBU
and already a captain.
暗部の隊長では
いちばん若いだろう。
He must be the youngest captain
the ANBU has ever had.
新しい班の隊員は
わしの暗部から出すことにする。
I shall assign my ANBU agents
to this new team.
（カカシ）お前は　ダンゾウ様の暗部に
移るということか。
So does that mean you're going to
be transferred to Lord Danzo's ANBU?
どうなのでしょう？
I wonder?
Try not to get caught in between
the political wrangling of the higher-ups.
上の政治的かけ引きに
巻き込まれるなよ。
カカシ隊長。
Captain Kakashi...
この２年間
お世話になりました。
Thank you for the past two years.
おいおい　部署が変わるだけで
同じ木ノ葉の忍でしょ。
Come on now.
You're only changing sections.
You're still a Hidden Leaf shinobi.
遠くへ行っちまうわけじゃ
ないんだから。
It's not like you're going far away.
TRAINING GROUND THREE
（テンゾウ）１３歳ですよ。
He's 13 years old.
それを暗部の隊長にですか。
And they're making him a captain?
（カカシ）まぁ
ただの忍じゃないからな。
Well, he's an extraordinary shinobi.
（テンゾウ）写輪眼を持つとはいえ
１３で隊長とは　大抜擢ですよ。
Sure, he has the Sharingan.
But making captain at 13 is unheard of.
どうした？　夕顔。
What's up, Yugao?
（夕顔）今日から
ろ班に配置換えになりました。
I've been assigned to Team Ro,
starting from today.
お前が補充要員か。
So you're the replacement?
よろしくお願いします
カカシ先輩。
I'll do my best, Kakashi Senpai.
（フガク）よし　気をつけ！
All right. Attention!
お前たちの規律ある行動に
期待する。
I'm looking forward to your good work.
– Yes, sir!
（みんな）はっ！
警務部隊が　武装を強化している
という報告があがってきた。
I've gotten reports that the Police Force
is strengthening their armaments.
これが意味するところは何だ？
What do you make of this?
うちはの　里への不満が→
Dissatisfaction towards the Hidden Leaf
is running high among the Uchiha.
再び高まっています。
このままでは　いかんか。
はい。
We can't ignore it anymore, it seems.
Yes...
You are aware of
the Leaf's barrier system?
木ノ葉の結界システムのことは
知っておるな。
無断で里へ侵入した者を
感知するやつですね。
It senses when the Village
has been infiltrated.
その結界を　何者かがすり抜け→
Someone has been getting through
the barrier undetected.
里へ侵入を
繰り返しておるようじゃ。
結界を抜ける暗号の術式は→
Even among the Hidden Leaf,
木ノ葉でも　一部の者しか
知らぬはずなのだが。
only a few know the secret code
to pass through the barrier.
Either there's a traitor in our midst,
裏切り者がもらしたか→
結界術を破る方法を持つ術者が
いるかである。
or a jutsu user who
can break the barrier.
裏切り者なら　術式を変更して
あぶり出すこともできるが→
If it's a traitor,
we can smoke him out by changing
the jutsu formula.
I believe it's someone capable of
passing through the barrier with a jutsu.
わしは　結界をすり抜ける術者が
いると考えている。
I don't want to believe that.
認めたくはありませんが…。
I want you to look into this.
お前に　この件を
調べてもらいたいのだ。
部分結界システムの配置図だ。
This is a chart of the barrier placements.
The alert is high in some spots.
特に反応頻度の高い地域がある。
ここは？
うちは地区の周辺だ。
Where is this?
The area around Uchiha District.
If possible, we'd like to install
a barrier system there,
できれば　中に結界システムを
配置したいが→
but it's a self-governing district
and our hands are tied.
あそこは　彼らの自治区だから
手が出せない。
Make sure your investigation
does not trace back to the ANBU.
暗部の調査とはわからぬように
頼むぞ。
（ガイ）ん？
（ナルト）いいか？
Get this!
There's no way
I'm going to lose to you!
ぜってぇ　お前なんかに
負けねえかんな！
（サスケ）勝手にほえてろ。
うるせぇ！
Keep on blabbing.
Shut up!
うるさいのは　お前だよ。
You shut up.
ふぅ～。
妙な場所にいたな。
Curious finding you here.
今更　アカデミーで何だ？
実は今度　俺→
What brings you to the Academy
after so long?
I've been appointed a jonin leader,
in charge of the genin.
担当上忍を
やることになったんだ。
へぇ～　お前が下忍を預かるのか。
おうよ。
So you're going to look after the genin?
But I'm a bit worried about
the kind of students I'm getting.
しかし　いったい
どんな生徒を受け持つのか→
正直　不安だ。
Quit acting so high and mighty, Sasuke!
すかしてんじゃねえよ　サスケ！
お前は　うっとうしいんだよ。
You're so annoying.
うるせぇ！
Why you…!
ハハハッ！　ああいう生徒だと
苦労するかもしれんな。
Students like that will
be hard to handle.
ちょっと　つきあってくれ。
Come with me, will you?
何だ　勝負か？
散歩だ。
You want to spar?
Let's just take a walk.
ここは
うちは一族の地区じゃないのか？
This is the Uchiha District.
街並みに風情があるぞ。
This part of town has character.
入るのは初めてだ。
It's the first time
I've been here in a long time.
I used to come here a lot...
俺は何度か来ている　昔な。
long ago.
おぉ～　確かに
風情のあるせんべい屋だ。
Now that's a rice cracker shop
with character.
((おい　何をしている？
Hey, what're you doing?
It's way past our rendezvous time.
(集合時間は
とっくに過ぎてんだぞ))
この家が　どうした？
いや。
Is there something special
about this house?
It's nothing.
しかし　このせんべいは
うまいな。
These rice crackers are really good.
They're worth coming all the way here for.
わざわざ買いに来る価値はあるな。
他にも
ここならではの名物がある。
They've got some other stuff
you can only find here.
You've got to show me!
頼む　教えてくれ。
ここが何だ？
Where are we?
Nakano Shrine,
home of the Uchiha's patron deity.
うちはの氏神を祀る南賀ノ神社だ。
I'm an agnostic.
俺は　無宗教だ。
まぁまぁ　そう言わずに
おみくじでも引いていかない？
Just be a sport and go pull
a fortune for yourself.
ふむ…。
カカシ隊長！
イタチ。
Captain Kakashi!
Itachi...
どうして　ここに？
What are you doing here?
ちょっと昔を思い出してな。
お前は？
I was thinking about
something from the past.
How about you?
俺は　ここの人間ですよ。
よく来ます。
I'm from here.
I come here often.
隊長になってから　どうだ？
How is it being a captain?
別に変わりません。
There's no change.
I have the same kind of missions.
同じような任務をこなしています。
そうか。
I see...
おい　カカシ　大吉だ！
Hey, Kakashi!
I got "Excellent Luck"!
I drew "Excellent Luck"!
大吉が出たぞ！
侵入者が何者であれ→
There's not enough intel to
figure out who the infiltrator is
その目的を絞り込むだけの
情報が足りません。
or what he wants.
部分結界システムに
それぞれ人員を配置し→
We need to place agents at
every section of the barrier system
結界班と連携して
反応があれば対応する。
to coordinate with the barrier team.
Without infiltration tactics,
it's impossible to track down the culprit.
といった　人海戦術を
展開しないかぎり→
侵入者の発見は無理ですね。
Unfortunately, we can't spare
the manpower for such an operation.
今　この件に　そこまでの人員を
割く余裕はないのう。
警務部隊に
パトロールを強化してもらうしか→
All we can do is to ask the Police Force
to step up their patrols, but…
ないでしょうが…。
どうした？
What is it?
Well…
いえ　久しぶりに
うちは地区へ行ったんですが→
I went to the Uchiha District
for the first time in a long time.
なんかこう昔とは
雰囲気が違いましてね。
Something about the atmosphere
had changed.
ピリピリしてるというか…。
I'd describe it as...tense.
閉鎖的であったか。
Were they antisocial?
Yes, they were. It felt like
they didn't want any outsiders there.
そうですね
一族以外の者が入るのを→
嫌う雰囲気がありました。
I see...
そうか　警務部隊の件は
上層部で検討する。
I'll discuss the Police Force
with the executive committee.
この任務は終了でよい。
You have completed your mission.
好都合だ　里の防衛を名目に
新たに　パトロール隊を組織する。
How convenient.
Under the pretext of village security,
we'll create a new patrol unit.
うちはの警務部隊から
職務を移行し→
We'll switch over duties from the Police Force
and reduce their strength.
戦力を削ぐのだ。
いや　それでは→
No, that will only incite the Uchiha.
逆に　うちはの反発を招く！
パトロール隊は警務部隊で組織させ→
We'll make the Police Force
oversee the patrols
逆に彼らの役割を
増やしてやるのだ。
and increase their workload.
クーデターの芽を
摘まねばならぬときに→
At a time when we should
be stopping their coup d'état,
うちはの戦力を
増やして　どうするのだ！
why would you increase
the Uchiha's power?
I will not allow the Uchiha
to stage a coup d'état!
うちはに　クーデターは起こさせぬ！
That goes without saying!
As if we'd let them.
当然だ　起こさせてなるものか！
Calm down, both of you.
２人とも落ち着け。
We don't know if there will
be a coup or not.
クーデターが起きるかどうかは
まだ　わからぬ。
We should bide our time and
see how it pans out.
もうしばらく　このまま
様子を見るのはどうか。
そのために我らには
イタチがおるのだろう？
That is why we have Itachi.
Isn't that right?
Isn't Itachi coming?
イタチは来ないのか？
（フガク）任務だそうだ。
He's on a mission.
The Uchiha Clan intends to
revolt against the Hidden Leaf.
うちは一族は木ノ葉に
革命を起こす決意です。
What?
なんじゃと？
You obtained proof of that?
証拠をつかんだのだな。
Yes...
はい。
（イタチ）おい。
Hey.
There's something I want you
to help me with.
アンタに協力して
もらいたいことがある。
うちはに　クーデターは起こさせぬ。
I will not let the Uchiha stage
a coup d'état.
そのことだけは　わしもおぬしも
同じ考えのはずだ。
That's one thing we agree on.
うむ。
待て　まだ結論は…。
Hold on now! We haven't come to
a conclusion yet!
うちはが準備を整えている以上→
If the Uchiha are getting ready to act,
we must prepare too.
こちらも準備しておかねばならん。
準備だけだぞ　ダンゾウ。
Preparations only, Danzo.
（イタチ）今夜　決行する。
Tonight is the night.
いいだろう。
約束どおり　手を貸してやる。
Fine. I shall assist you as promised.
では　手はずどおりに頼む。
I'm counting on you.
俺が　うちは殲滅に手を貸すのは
復讐の他に別の目的があるからだ。
I'm going to help you annihilate
the Uchiha
because I have another goal.
それには目をつぶってもらうぞ。
I want you to keep
your "eyes closed" for that...
この写輪眼を
お前のやることに向けるなと？
So I'm not to use my Sharingan against
whatever you're planning?
そうだ　それが　俺が
お前の弟を殺さぬ証しでもある。
Yes.
Then I will guarantee that
I will not kill your little brother...
写輪眼を持たぬ子供に用はない。
I have no use for a child
without the Sharingan.
だから安心しろ　か。
And that's supposed to reassure me?
俺にはもう　アンタを
信頼するしか道はないんだがな。
At this point, I have no other choice
but to trust you.
行き場を失ったら俺の組織へ来い。
If you need a place to go,
join my organization.
アンタの組織？
名は暁。
Your organization?
I call it the Akatsuki.
ANBU
（テンゾウ）第一級警戒態勢です。
It's an Emergency Alert, Level 1!
（カカシ）出動準備　急げ！
Get ready to move out! Hurry!
なんだ　貴様！
Identify yourself!
出動！
Move out!
わしの班は
木ノ葉警務部隊本部へ。
My team will go to the Hidden Leaf
Police Force Headquarters!
わしの班は　うちは地区だ。
My team will go to Uchiha District!
ひでぇ。
いったい何が？
This is horrible!
What the hell?
生存者を確保せよ。
Rescue anyone who is still alive!
生存者　１名発見。
There's a survivor!
医療班へ運べ。
Take him to the Medical Unit!
他はみんな　やられています。
Everyone else is dead.
遺体はすべて回収せよ。
Take away the corpses.
よいな？　すべてだ。
屋内も見逃すでないぞ。
I mean, every single one.
Check inside the buildings as well.
しかし　これはいったい
何者の仕業なんです？
Who could have done such a thing?
（ダンゾウ）うちはイタチだ。
イタチが？
Itachi Uchiha.
Itachi?!
うちはイタチは
己の一族を嫌い　憎んでいた。
Itachi Uchiha despised his clan.
そこで
うちはシスイを殺し　その眼を奪い→
That is why he killed Shisui
and took his eyes,
うちはの同胞と
争いごとを引き起こした。
and caused in-fighting among
his brethren...and then finally...
そして　とうとう
この凶行に及んだのだ。
He caused this atrocity.
アイツが？　そんな…。
But, why would he...?
グズグズするな　作業にかかれ！
Enough talking. Get to work!
これですべて解決したな。
This settles everything.
何が解決だ？
What does this settle?
わしらの喉元に　太い骨が
突き刺さったということが→
Don't you see the huge problem
we're left with?!
わからんのか？
ほんの小骨だ。
I consider it very minor.
ダンゾウよ　おぬしの独断専行を
もはや許してはおけぬ。
Danzo, I cannot allow you to act
on your own authority any longer.
今　このときより
火影の補佐役を解任する。
As of this moment,
you are relieved of your duties
as second in command.
しかし　ヒルゼン　わしは…。
But Hiruzen, I did it for...
里のためというのなら
うちは一族も里の者であった。
"The good of the Leaf"?
Well then, the Uchiha Clan belonged
to the Hidden Leaf.
おぬしの根の暗部も解体する。
Your ANBU and Foundation
will be dissolved!
追って正式に処遇を決める。
I will deal with you later.
それまで謹慎せよ。
Until then,
you are confined to your quarters!
ダンゾウ様　遺体の数が合いません。
Lord Danzo, the body count
doesn't match up.
なんだと？
What did you say?
消えたように
なくなっているのです。
It's like they just disappeared.
俺はすべてを見た。
I witnessed everything.
そして　これからも見ている。
And I will continue to watch.
お前がサスケに手を出せば→
If you as much as touch Sasuke,
里の機密情報すべてを
敵国に教えてやる。
I will pass on classified Village intel
to every enemy nation.
おのれ…。
Damn you...
これが　イタチの
憎しみからだというのなら→
If this is the scope of Itachi's hatred,
it ran very, very deep...
根が深いですね。
生存者が　たった一人なんて。
Just one survivor...
運び出すぞ。
はい。
Start taking them away.
Yes, sir.
暗部とはいえ　なんて任務だ。
What a mission, even for an ANBU.
ん？
《アイツ　どうしたんだ？》
What's up with him?
コラッ！
Hey!
（アスマ）一族同胞皆殺しか。
The entire clan was annihilated...
皆殺しではない。
Not everyone.
I hear one child survived.
子供が一人生き残っているそうだ。
（アスマ）同じことだ。　うちは一族は
壊滅させられたんだよ。
What's the difference?
The Uchiha Clan is extinct.
それも　たった一人にな。
All except one.
うちはイタチが
ビンゴブック入りするなんて→
I never imagined that Itachi Uchiha
would be placed in the Bingo Book.
思いもしませんでしたよ。
しかも　いきなりＳクラス入り。
ITACHI UCHIHA
In the S-class right from the start.
まっ　あれだけの同胞を
殺したんですから。
Well, he slaughtered so many of his clan...
どうしました？　先輩。
What's wrong, Senpai?
結局　俺は　アイツのことを→
It just goes to show
I knew nothing about him.
何も知らなかったということか。
何も理解していなかったんだな。
I understood nothing.
そういえば　うちは地区ですが
取り壊すそうですね。
By the way, I hear Uchiha District
will be razed to the ground.
壊す？
Razed?
NO TRESPASSING
A terrible incident took place there.
No one would want to go near it.
あれだけの事件の起きた
場所ですから→
今のままじゃ
誰も寄りつこうとはしませんよ。
オビト…　あれから俺は
何をやってるんだろうな？
Obito...
What have I been doing...
since that day?
何か言いたいことがあって
来たのだろう？
I know you have something to say...
人払いをしておいた。
No one is with me.
（イタチ）ご配慮　感謝します。
Thank you for your consideration.
まずは礼を言う。
First, you have my gratitude.
これで　木ノ葉は内戦を免れた。
Civil war has been averted
in Hidden Leaf Village.
里の平和は守られたのだ。
はい。
Peace in the village has been maintained.
Yes.
しかし　他の手段は
なかったものか　と→
But even so, I regret that
there was no other way.
今も　残念に思っておる。
申し訳ありません。
I'm sorry.
謝るのは　わしだ。
I am the one who must apologize.
これより　木ノ葉は
お前を　一族殺しの抜け忍とし→
Henceforth, you will be branded
a Rogue Ninja who killed his entire clan...
ビンゴブックに載せ
生死を問わず捜索する。
And be listed in the Bingo Book
as a fugitive, wanted dead or alive.
当然です。
That goes without saying.
What will you do now?
これからどうする？
暁と名乗る組織の
手を借りました。
I've enlisted the aid of a group
named Akatsuki.
その者が約束を違えぬように
そばに身をおくことにします。
I intend to stay close to them to
make sure a promise is not broken.
暁に入るというのか？
You're joining the Akatsuki?
サスケの命を守るために　三代目も
それを確約　願えますか？
Lord Third, will you swear to me
that you will protect Sasuke?
お前の弟は　これまで同様→
Your younger brother will continue
to study at the Academy
他の子と同じようにアカデミーに通い→
木ノ葉の忍として
育つであろう。
and grow up to become
a Hidden Leaf shinobi.
何一つ　不自由はさせぬが→
He will want for nothing, however...
お前への憎しみまでは
取り除くことはできぬぞ。
I will not be able to erase
his hatred towards you.
その憎しみ
背負う覚悟はできています。
I am prepared to bear his hatred.
もう行け！　里を包む
結界の術式は変更せずにおく。
Now go...
I will leave the jutsu formula for
the barrier around the Village unchanged.
サスケのことが心配なら
いつでも忍び込んでまいれ。
三代目…。
あなたの
その優しさを→
うちはの者たちが
理解しなかったのが残念です。
なに　わしは　ただ甘いだけよ。
それゆえに
この悲劇を生んだのだ。
ダンゾウの根の者と
わしの暗部の者を再編成し→
人員を他に
振り向けようと思っている。
警務部隊を
新たに立ち上げねばならぬしな。
うむ…
警務部隊は一族にとらわれず→
広く人材を集めよう。
里の将来を見据え
適材を適所に配置せねば。
お呼びでしょうか？
のう　カカシよ。
お前が暗部に入って何年になる？
四代目のときに入隊してから
１０年近くになるでしょうか。
もともとは　お前が抱えた
心の闇を晴らしてやろうと→
ミナトはお前に暗部をやらせたのだ。
自分のそばに
お前を置いておくために。
そんな気はしていました。
そのミナトが死に
わしが火影に再任されたとき→
ミナトの暗部を　そのまま受け継いだ。
だが
わしのそばに置いたところで→
お前の闇が　晴れるものではない。
むしろ深まるばかりだ。
その面を取れ！
１０年か。
ちと　お前に頼りすぎたな。
ここに　暗部の任を解く！
そして　新たな任務を言い渡す。
はっ！
担当上忍をやれ！
はあ？
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
[スピーカ]美空ひばりです。
[スピーカ]では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』→
２時間スペシャル！
今回は　ご覧の豪華な
歌手の皆さんによる→